const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="insurance",a=200,n=120,o=[{id:186,question:"Any information that will influence a prudent insurer is called",option:{a:"contract",b:"misrepresentation",c:"disclosure",d:"Material facts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:301,question:"Insurance against risk is possible because of the law of",option:{a:"large numbers",b:"few numbers",c:"inverse proportion",d:"diminishing returns"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:117,question:"There must  be  a  close  connection  between  the loss actually suffered and the risk is relating to the principle  of",option:{a:"Abandonment",b:"Proximate cause",c:"Utmost good faith",d:"Adhesion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:37,question:"Which  of the following activities is  not a  function of the  Chartered  Insurance  Institute  of  Nigeria?",option:{a:"Setting a standard for members",b:"Promoting Professional growth",c:"Promoting the interest of insurers",d:"Specifying professional qualification"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:192,question:"The process of changing anything wrong with the policy to make it current is",option:{a:"Endorsement",b:"Specification",c:"Rectification",d:"Correction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:230,question:"one of these is a content of a proposal form",option:{a:"children of the proposer",b:"education of the proposer",c:"occupation of the proposer",d:"educational"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:314,question:"In which of the following policies is <em>certificate of insurance</em>  used?",option:{a:"Burglary insurance",b:"Product liability insurance",c:"Employer’s liability insurance",d:"Money insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:108,question:"Which of the following is not a function of insurance?",option:{a:"Serves as collateral",b:"Encouraging saving",c:"Provides insecurity",d:"Reduces risks"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:163,question:"A  Statement signed by the insured, certifying the Statement",option:{a:"Certificate",b:"Declaration",c:"Confirmation slip",d:"Accuracy statement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:265,question:"Which of the following risks is covered by insurance policy?",option:{a:"an investment loss on the stock market",b:"dishonesty of an employee leading to fraud",c:"failure of a business venture",d:"rise and fall of prices of goods in the market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:39,question:"The payment made when the insured is  not  entitled to claim under a policy is",option:{a:"voluntary excess",b:"ex-gratia",c:"return premium",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:179,question:"The policy that covers loss of cash while in transit or at home is --------------- insurance",option:{a:"Burglary",b:"Business interruption",c:"Credit",d:"Money"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:150,question:"The legal right to insure a subject matter is",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Subject Matter",c:"Subrogation",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:224,question:"Risk that affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"pure risk",c:"fundamental risk",d:"static risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:136,question:"The amount given to the insured if he does not want the contract to continue is called",option:{a:"Insurance broker",b:"Premium",c:"Surrender value",d:"Assessor loss adjuster"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:133,question:"When an insured person admits that he has indemnified, he means that",option:{a:"The damage proper by has been recovered",b:"He was paid premium fully",c:"The insurance company has restored him to his former position",d:"He was paid his premium fully"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:287,question:"Partial loss can be divided into",option:{a:"particular average and general average",b:"particular average and total loss",c:"actual loss and total loss",d:"total loss and particular loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:2,question:"One of the objectives of buying a term assurance policy is to",option:{a:"protect  dependants  in  case  of  death  of  the  life assured",b:"reduce financial burden of the life assured",c:"supplement retirement income  of  the  life  assured",d:"maximize savings from the life assured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:204,question:"The insured is also known as",option:{a:"the client",b:"the consumer",c:"the policy holder",d:"agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:177,question:"Any circumstance that promotes the probability of a loss is called",option:{a:"Accident",b:"Hazard",c:"Loss",d:"Risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:72,question:"The risks which affect the society and whose causes are beyond human control is",option:{a:"particular risk",b:"static",c:"fundamental",d:"speculative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:127,question:"Re-insurance contract is between",option:{a:"Re-insurer and insurer",b:"Re- insurance and insurance",c:"Co-insurer and insurer",d:"Insurance broker and re-insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:174,question:"A marine policy that provider cover for the construction of sea vessels is called --------- policy",option:{a:"Building",b:"Mixed",c:"Port",d:"Valued"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:162,question:"The essential value of valid contract that states that the parties to a contract must be in perfect agreement and have a common mind is",option:{a:"Consideration",b:"Perpetual existence",c:"Excess",d:"Consensus ad-idem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:173,question:"The following are types of life assurances,  except",option:{a:"annuity",b:"Endowment",c:"Hire purchase",d:"Whole life"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:51,question:"The primary function of insurance is",option:{a:"making profit",b:"managing of risk",c:"spreading of risk",d:"prevention of accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:55,question:"A  statement  of  fact  that  the insured must have an interest in the object of the contract is called",option:{a:"warranty",b:"insurable interest",c:"subrogation",d:"object interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:344,question:"Life  assurance  contract is useful to a policyholder in the area of",option:{a:"production",b:"protection",c:"industrialization",d:"rehabilitation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:190,question:"When an   insurer agrees   to   replace   irreparably damaged or stolen goods with similar type it is called",option:{a:"Reinstatement",b:"Cash",c:"Repairs",d:"Replacement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:318,question:"The policy that covers  an  insured  employee  against injury  sustained  in  the  course  of  employment  is",option:{a:"professional indemnity",b:"product liability",c:"public liability",d:"employer’s liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:302,question:"Which  of  the  following  is  not  a  component  of  an insurance policy?",option:{a:"Signature clause",b:"Particular clause",c:"Recital clause",d:"Operative clause"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:93,question:"Subrogation principle can be applied in the following insurance policies except in",option:{a:"aviation policy",b:"engineering policy",c:"life policy",d:"marine policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:100,question:"Unlawful breaking and entering into any premises or place of safe keeping is covered under which of these policies?",option:{a:"burglary",b:"business interruption",c:"employers liability",d:"public liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:345,question:"Which  of  the  following  functions  is  related  to  life assurance contract? Benefits are",option:{a:"determined  on  the  happening  of  insured  event",b:"determined by the indemnity doctrine",c:"determined at the inception of the policy",d:"assessed by the extent of the loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:319,question:"What is  the  maximum  liability which the insurer can pay on a particular loss?",option:{a:"Average",b:"Sum insured",c:"Franchise",d:"Excess"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:17,question:"How much premium will the insurer charge?",option:{a:"N= 3,750",b:"N= 13,750",c:"N= 17,500",d:"N= 31,250"},section:"XYC Industries Limited proposed a fire risk to Adequate Insurance Plc. on a total sum insured of N= 5,000,000.00. The risk was accepted on a premium rate of 0.35%. After survey, the insurer charged a rate of 0.275%.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:172,question:"A financial compensation sufficient to return the insured back to his original position after loss is known as",option:{a:"Deposit",b:"Loan",c:"Indemnity",d:"Overdraft"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:116,question:"The principle that requires the insured to disclose to the insurer all matters relating to the object of insurance is called",option:{a:"Uberrimae fidei",b:"Proximate cause",c:"Abandonment",d:"Subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:95,question:"The person  that  brings  an insurance  contract  into existence between  the principal and third party  is a/an",option:{a:"agent",b:"bailee",c:"contractor",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:48,question:"A <em>revival clause</em> in a life policy will allow an insured to revive a policy that lapsed on account of nonpayment of premium, provided the insured",option:{a:"can prove he is sick at the time",b:"cannot fall sick after the policy",c:"can prove he is in good health",d:"can recover from the ill health"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:161,question:"------------- is a policy designed to place the insured in the same financial position as he was immediately before the happening of the event insured against",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Subrogation",c:"Surrender value",d:"Actuary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:215,question:"With insurance contract there is",option:{a:"certainty of occurrence",b:"uncertainty of occurrence",c:"certainty of reward",d:"uncertainty  of reward"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:76,question:"The following are insurable except",option:{a:"Marine",b:"Goods",c:"Gambling",d:"Accident"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:134,question:"A house worth N=60,000 insured against fire for N=40,000.  Fire destroyed and cause damage worth N=30,000. On the house under which insurance principle will the owner be entitled to compensation of N=30,000.",option:{a:"Contribution",b:"Subrogation",c:"indemnity",d:"Uberrimae fidei"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:175,question:"Spreading of risk to ensure that no insurer is liquidated by the occurrence of a large loss is the concept of",option:{a:"Insurance",b:"Re insurance",c:"Renewal",d:"Treaty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:341,question:"The right of choice of option for method of indemnity is exercised by the",option:{a:"insured",b:"insurance broker",c:"insurance consultant",d:"insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:324,question:"Insurance is described as a risk",option:{a:"avoidance mechanism",b:"regulating mechanism",c:"transfer mechanism",d:"assessment mechanism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:126,question:"Uncertainty of loss is known as",option:{a:"Risk",b:"Certainty",c:"Insurance",d:"Hazard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:334,question:"The process of  assessing  risks  in  insurance  and classifying them according to their degree of insurability so  that  the  appropriate  rate  may  be  assigned  is",option:{a:"inspecting",b:"underwriting",c:"surveying",d:"evaluating"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:296,question:"The maximum number of days allowed for a policy holder to pay his renewal premium after it has become due is called",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"conditions",c:"days of grace",d:"days of liberty"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:160,question:"The monetary consideration paid by the insured to the insurers for the insurance granted by the policy is called",option:{a:"Premium",b:"Money",c:"Price",d:"Benefit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:99,question:"A policy designed to protect individuals against negligence while carrying out their daily activities is called",option:{a:"business interruption",b:"employers liability",c:"engineering",d:"professional indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:203,question:"The premium paid by the insured to the insurance company is",option:{a:"capital",b:"commission",c:"common fund",d:"consideration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:33,question:"George effected two personal accident policies. The first policy provides N= 25,000.00 cover for loss of limb. The second policy provides N= 30,000.00 cover for loss of limb. What is the total amount that  George  will receive in the event of a valid loss of limb claim?",option:{a:"N= 5,000.00",b:"N= 25,000.00",c:"N= 30,000.00",d:"N= 55,000.00"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:14,question:"Abandonment is mostly applicable to",option:{a:"marine insurance",b:"motor insurance",c:"fire insurance",d:"engineering insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:7,question:"In  classification  of  risks, what is the name given to a risk  where  the  causes  of  events are linked to factors 	that are due to the society we live in?",option:{a:"Dynamic risk",b:"Particular risk",c:"Speculative risk",d:"Fundamental risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:298,question:"The cause of a loss is",option:{a:"peril",b:"hazard",c:"risk",d:"loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:103,question:"Below are insurable policies except",option:{a:"Earthquake",b:"Fire",c:"Life",d:"Marine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:83,question:"The  principle  of  insurance  which  states  that a person must be in a legally recognized relationship to what is  insured  such  that  he  will  benefit  from its existence or suffer by its loss is",option:{a:"utmost good faith",b:"insurable interest",c:"proximate cause",d:"subrogation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:32,question:"A contract sold  by  insurance companies that  pay  a monthly or  quarterly income  benefit for the  life  of a person is",option:{a:"endowment",b:"annuity",c:"income",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:237,question:"A card used by motorist in the West African sub-region is called",option:{a:"insurance certificate",b:"insurance register",c:"insurance green card",d:"Ecowas brown card"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:60,question:"An individual who is interested in taking an insurance policy must fill a form of application called:",option:{a:"premium slip",b:"policy document",c:"proposal form",d:"claim form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:232,question:"When the proposer fails to fill the proposal form truthfully, the contract will become",option:{a:"voidable",b:"illegal",c:"void",d:"enforceable"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:71,question:"The uncertainty as to the occurrence of a loos is",option:{a:"Hazard",b:"Loss",c:"Risk",d:"insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:43,question:"To which of the following parties does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"The proposer only",b:"The insurer only",c:"The insurer and proposer",d:"The third party and insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:166,question:"Another name for consequential loss is",option:{a:"Stop loss",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Business interruption insurance",d:"Excess loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:105,question:"Which of the following is not a principle of insurance?",option:{a:"Indemnity",b:"Compensation",c:"Proximate cause",d:"Insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:273,question:"A residential building built beside a petrol filling station is described as a",option:{a:"risk",b:"hazard",c:"peril",d:"liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:6,question:"Which  of  the  following  risks  is  covered  by  insurance policy?",option:{a:"An investment loss on the stock market",b:"Dishonesty of an employee leading to fraud",c:"Failure of a business venture",d:"Rise and fall of prices of goods in the market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:250,question:"The deliberate throwing overboard of part of a cargo without a good intention is called",option:{a:"jettison",b:"barratry",c:"voyaging",d:"overboard"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:62,question:"The temporary document issued by the insurer to the insured while the policy is being prepared is",option:{a:"insurance certificate",b:"promissory note",c:"exchange slip",d:"cover note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:346,question:"The saving element in a permanent life assurance policy which represent the policyholder’s interest in the policy is",option:{a:"surrender value",b:"cash value",c:"sum assured",d:"residual value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:320,question:"A policy taken to cover several shipments for a sum assured is",option:{a:"floating policy",b:"valued policy",c:"declaration policy",d:"special policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:249,question:"The deliberate throwing overboard of part of a cargo to lighten the ship is called",option:{a:"barratry",b:"overthrown",c:"voyaging",d:"jettisoning"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:149,question:"The wrongful act willfully committed by either the master or the prejudice of either the owner or crew to the chatterer of the ship is",option:{a:"Barratry",b:"Caveat emptor",c:"Bailee",d:"Jettison"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:167,question:"Subrogation principle can be applied in the following insurance policies except in -------- policy",option:{a:"Life",b:"Motor",c:"Theft",d:"Burglary"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:144,question:"The date on which an insurance or reinsurance contract comes into force is known as",option:{a:"Starting point date",b:"Inception date",c:"Beginning date",d:"Commencement date"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:208,question:"An undertaking by the insured that certain things shall be done or not be done or certain things shall be put in place or not in place is called",option:{a:"warranties and representation",b:"utmost good faith and uberrimae fidei",c:"insurable and non-insurable",d:"subrogation and indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:293,question:"The form of risk that can easily be calculated and estimated is known as",option:{a:"non insurable risk",b:"non-financial risk",c:"speculative risk",d:"insurable risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:27,question:"One of the information contained in a renewal notice is the",option:{a:"previous losses",b:"location of the risk",c:"occupation of the insured",d:"sum insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:286,question:"The amount given to the insured if he does not want the contract to continue is called",option:{a:"premium",b:"price",c:"consideration",d:"surrender value"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:64,question:"Which of these is an aid to trade?",option:{a:"cover note",b:"insurance",c:"premium",d:"policy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:112,question:"Hazard that deals with the human habits and character that arises from human attitude and the conduct of people is called",option:{a:"physical",b:"Moral",c:"Static",d:"Dynamic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:159,question:"The price of insurance is known as",option:{a:"Rate",b:"Interest",c:"Premium",d:"Profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:53,question:"An insurance principle that requires the insured to be honest and disclose all relevant facts is called",option:{a:"subrogation",b:"utmost good faith",c:"proximate cause",d:"insurable interest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:231,question:"The statement “ I to the best of my knowledge hereby confirm that the statements contained in this prosal form are true and correct” represents",option:{a:"confirmation",b:"declaration",c:"witnessing",d:"humility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:139,question:"Consequential loss is also known as",option:{a:"Business interruption insurance",b:"Credit insurance",c:"Excess loss",d:"Property insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:92,question:"Another name for business interruption insurance is",option:{a:"property insurance",b:"consequential loss",c:"credit insurance",d:"excess loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:241,question:"Policy condition which are automatically applicable and not stated in the contract of agreement is known as",option:{a:"agreed condition",b:"agreed negotiation",c:"implied condition",d:"expressed condition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:98,question:"Engineering insurance covers the following except",option:{a:"boiler explosion",b:"building and civil",c:"business interruption",d:"machinery breakdown"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:68,question:"The buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"Agent",b:"Broker",c:"Insured",d:"Insurer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:233,question:"Proposal form is used in the following classes of insurance except",option:{a:"Accident",b:"theft",c:"life",d:"large risk of fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:277,question:"policy designed for the insured who is incapacitated to carry out normal duty is",option:{a:"medical expenses",b:"temporary disablement",c:"permanent disablement",d:"medical expenses"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:219,question:"A seller of insurance product is",option:{a:"insurer",b:"promisor",c:"client",d:"insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:107,question:"Insurance was developed as a result of the existence of",option:{a:"Hazards",b:"Loss",c:"Risk",d:"Indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"},{id:154,question:"---------- is the evidence cover of the risk given to the insured by the insurer",option:{a:"Cover",b:"Policy",c:"Claim",d:"Compensation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:257,question:"One of the following is legally used by the insured while the policy is being processed",option:{a:"indemnity form",b:"claim form",c:"cover note",d:"proposal form"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:330,question:"The amount payable to an insured in the event of fire damage of household items is the",option:{a:"cost of repair",b:"actual cash value",c:"replacement cost",d:"sum insured"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:8,question:"The evidence of the insurance contract is",option:{a:"proposal form",b:"policy",c:"schedule",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:201,question:"Insurance is defined as",option:{a:"risking of loss",b:"pooling of risk",c:"gathering of risk",d:"waiving of risk"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:256,question:"Another name for the assured is",option:{a:"insurance company’s client",b:"insurance broker",c:"insurance company",d:"insurance agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:220,question:"A buyer of insurance product is",option:{a:"insured",b:"promise",c:"insurer",d:"insuree"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:57,question:"The object of an insurance policy is equally known as",option:{a:"insurance title",b:"insurance premium",c:"subject matter",d:"risk object"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:28,question:"Family income option in a life policy provides that",option:{a:"the beneficiary will be paid for life",b:"the beneficiary receives the policy sum",c:"interest will be added monthly",d:"salary will be paid to the insured until death"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:34,question:"Renewal notice is  used by  insurers  to  remind the insured of the",option:{a:"reduction of cover",b:"continuation of cover",c:"expiration of cover",d:"increase of cover"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:266,question:"One of this is the evidence of insurance contract",option:{a:"schedule",b:"policy",c:"proposal form",d:"endorsement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:269,question:"To which of the following does the principle of utmost good faith apply in a contract of insurance?",option:{a:"the insurer only",b:"the proposer only",c:"the third party and insured",d:"insurer and proposer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:222,question:"A contract that is contrary to public policy is",option:{a:"valid contract",b:"legal contract",c:"illegal contract",d:"voidable contract"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:183,question:"Which of these is insurable?",option:{a:"Fire",b:"Inflation",c:"Bad publicity",d:"Riot and war"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:52,question:"An  insurance  feature  that  requires  the  parties  to disclose  all  material  facts  about  the  agreement is known as",option:{a:"Adhesion",b:"Disclosure",c:"Material fact",d:"Utmost good faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:3,question:"An assurance policy taken by experts to cover possible negligence arising from their duties is",option:{a:"consequential loss",b:"professional indemnity",c:"cargo",d:"freight"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:291,question:"The full meaning of NAICOM is",option:{a:"Nigerian insurance company",b:"national insurance commission",c:"national insurer commission",d:"national insured commission"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:338,question:"The amount charged when a ship overstays at the port under a marine contract is",option:{a:"penalty",b:"fine",c:"overcharge",d:"demurrage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:4,question:"The class of insurance that  covers  legal  liability to a third party for bodily injury and property damage caused by goods supplied is",option:{a:"employer’s liability",b:"public liability",c:"professional indemnity",d:"products liability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2014"},{id:56,question:"A fundamental condition which must be filled  by the  insured for compensation is",option:{a:"warranty",b:"obligation",c:"interest",d:"premium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"1"},{id:299,question:"The party who proposes to the insurance company to insure his properly is called",option:{a:"offeree",b:"offeror",c:"acceptance party",d:"offer client"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:262,question:"One of this is a method of claim settlement",option:{a:"price",b:"trade by barter",c:"exchange",d:"cash"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"5"},{id:247,question:"Third party provides cover only for damages to",option:{a:"assurer",b:"insurer",c:"2nd party",d:"another person"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"4"},{id:156,question:"A temporary certificate to show that a cover is in existence is called",option:{a:"Policy",b:"Certificate",c:"Cover note",d:"Claim slip"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"3"},{id:109,question:"In the utmost good faith principle, the value of the subject matter should",option:{a:"Be over stated",b:"Understated",c:"Not be stated",d:"Not be overstated nor understated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"model",examyear:"2"}],t={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:o};export{o as data,t as default,e as message,a as status,i as subject,n as total};
